# VENKATESWARA REDDY CHAIKAM

+91 9515737356 | Ced19i019@iiitdm.ac.in | geekforgeeks profile

## About

I am a dedicated and skilled computer science student with a strong academic record and experience in software development. I have completed projects in HTML/CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, and Python and have earned certifications in Python programming and problem-solving. I have also successfully cleared JEE-ADVANCED and GATE examinations.

## Education

Indian Institute of Information Technology, Design and Manufacturing

Kancheepuram, Chennai

B. Tech + Integrated M. Tech in Computer Science - CGPA:8.06/10

Jul. 2019 - Present Vijayawada, Andhra Pradesh

Narayana Junior College Intermediate in MPC - CGPA:9.88/10

jun. 2017 - May 2019

#### Experience

## Software Developer intern (Remote)

Nov 2021 – Jan 2022

CPPSECRETS

Noida, UttarPradesh

• Wrote efficient code on Data Structure and Algorithm Problems

#### Placement Cell Coordinator

march 2022 – Present

IIITDM KANCHEEPURAM

Chennai, TamilNadu

• Guiding volunteers and interacting with companies

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:Python,C,C++, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS Frameworks: Node. js. Express, jQuery, mongoose, React

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB(Beginner)

Courses: Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating system, DBMS

#### Projects

## **SIMON GAME** | *HTML*, *CSS*, *jQuery*, *JavaScript*

• Developed a simple game that incorporated sound buttons, animations, and interactive features to enhance user experience. The game's sound buttons allowed users to activate different sounds such as background music and sound effects.

## Keeper App | React

• Developed a Front-End application using React that allows users to post and delete notes with titles and content. The app uses a responsive and user-friendly interface to make note-taking simple and intuitive.

## **To-Do List** | Express, Mongoose, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

• Developed a To-Do list using the Express framework and Mongoose library. The app allows users to create, update and delete tasks, with a user-friendly interface.

#### VLIW Processor | Python

• Designed a 64-bit Very Long Instruction Word (VLIW) processor capable of executing multiple instructions in parallel.

## Achievements And Certifications

- Successfully cleared JEE-ADVANCED and GATE examinations in 2019 and 2022 respectively.
- Earned a certificate from NPTEL for completing the Joy of Computing Using Python course, demonstrating proficiency in Python programming and problem-solving.